today's episode is going to be
very very different so as you might have
guessed by the title of this video we're
going to be doing a little world tour
now we're probably about
over halfway is all i can say i'm not
sure it's very difficult to tell how
long seasons last but we are over the
halfway point for absolute sure we've
been going
10 months oh wow it's bit it's been 10
months so
it's always good to take a little step
back and appreciate just how much has
been built
and done on the hermitcraft server and
seeing as it's just got to the end of a
big storyline the turf war and it's all
come to a conclusion i thought now is a
good time to show everyone around and
also for me to go and have a look
personally as i've not really seen a lot
of the hermit's base
so what we're gonna do is we're gonna
start from the very beginning and we're
gonna make our way round the hermitcraft
server and we're gonna do a little tour
so
let's begin and we're gonna start here
the humble beginnings
the green hobbit hole
now not a lot has changed in here i must
admit there is there is really not a lot
i remember digging this out and thinking
at the time that this cactus farm took a
really long time
but in hindsight it really didn't but
we're all familiar with this base and i
just wanted to point out that really not
a lot has changed pesky bird is still
here but one thing i haven't done for a
really long time is sent mumbo a message
yeah we'll send we'll send him a message
it's been a long time
feels like we're back at the start of
the season
oh man i remember that as well all right
go on
love letter to mumbo
he probably won't even visit his hobbit
hole so now let's take a good look and
start with our own mansion because this
is what i'm going to be coming back to
in the new year it's no secret that the
mansion has been slightly neglected and
i have to admit it's lacking a lot of
soul a lot of a lot of extra things that
bring it to life so we're going to
really tackle this thing and especially
the interior in the new year and i've
got some ideas finally and with the turf
war
wager being fulfilled scar is going to
help me
with this
so that should be really really good so
there's one thing that i really want to
point out in this tour immediately from
what looking at the mansion
it's i spent hours making a proper item
sorting system thinking that this would
solve a lot of my issues and this took
ages right
but yet
i still have an awful chest monster that
has built up
over time look at this just all of the
stuff
and to be honest with you this is just
something i can't be bothered to fix
i can't be bothered and if you're
wondering what this is this is the uh
gravestone i made for villager number
two he shall be replaced but we're all
familiar with the mansion so let's move
on to some of the stuff we haven't seen
in a while we're all kind of familiar
with the jungle gang over here but we're
gonna go and cycle through every single
hermits build so we might as well start
with our close neighbors
starting with scars jungle village which
is actually a really good
redstone farm like i thought that this
was a bit silly at the start and that he
went for
art over the function of it but actually
if you go in here i'm not sure how he's
linked it all up but this thing is
actually really really
productive and gives loads of stuff and
i've i've been steadily stealing melons
from here for a really long time please
don't tell scar
but this is scar's early build what he
actually spent a lot of his time on
is this scar x facility with the big
drill this is an absolutely phenomenal
build
and i'm not going to be ranking
everyone's builds because oh my goodness
i haven't seen this but i'm going to be
hopefully doing a top ten like my top 10
favorite builds
so expect that to come in the next few
days because it will be
amazing or a skull say
if i butchered that look at this so this
is the big drill that goes to the nether
and he has told this story with all of
the nether stuff coming out of the the
big hole it's ours
really really cool i i love that
attention to detail there so obviously
he's not finished and no one is finished
as far as i'm aware no one has finished
their mega base just as oh my goodness
look at the floating robot
just as i haven't finished my mansion
scar hasn't finished here so any
judgments we make are probably a bit
unfair but we're just here to appreciate
our fellow hermits and that moves us
quite swiftly over to mumbo's base
now mumbo's base is strange he went in a
completely different direction to what i
was expecting at the start of the season
so it started with the giant
circle of spanners that made it made it
look like a giant summoning circle and
then he went in a totally different
direction like he has the same kind of
build here with this structure
but then it's
really overgrown and stuff and it was it
was odd and then i was like oh okay
that's strange and then he built a heart
there and i was like okay that's really
strange so i've got to commend mumbo on
how unique this bass is because it is
really strange
and he's also seems to have
some kind of secret
thing here oh he's there
see if he notices the carrot
dropping down
i think i've stumbled on a secret of
some kind oh he's noticed he's noticed
away get away
[Laughter]
okay so that's mumbo's base now we have
a quick look at iskall's omega tree now
this hasn't changed uh an awful lot
over the last few months so i'm not sure
there's an awful lot to say but it is
enormous trees are very difficult to
make
and i think it shows it definitely shows
and remember wood is logs or one of the
the most grindy things to get
in the game and one thing i haven't
checked in a while is the giant message
so i've i've added a few words ethos
smells like beef and i haven't added
anything in a while and will fart
rainbows that
exude i think that that last one
that one's gotta be red
uh
farts rainbows that exude wow i don't
even know i don't even know what i don't
even know what to add to that so that's
the omega tree and then we've got
stresses base over here which is like a
fairy wonderland
inside the jungle
so this is again a very unique project
and i don't think there's anything quite
like it on the server and that's what we
got to commend about this this server is
it's absolute diversity of builds and
work done everyone has a different take
and everyone has their own art to
contribute and
you know at the start of the season i
thought oh man you know it felt like i
was really far away from everyone like
scar was pretty close but it took me a
while to walk to him as things have
built up you can start to see everyone's
base in the distance
and you kind of realize that the world
here has gotten so much smaller no i
forgot i don't need to sleep with beat
ups on the server so let's move on to
rendog's base which has got an very a
very very star warsy theme going for it
i remember helping him with this sort of
spaceport here trying to help him get
the shape right and he looks like he's
building some other stuff here now ren
didn't actually start his hermitcraft
season seven here he started way over
somewhere over there with as much
smaller base and he decided to move
closer to us in the jungle where a lot
of the a lot of the friends are you know
what i mean like there's a lot more
action going on he was feeling quite
isolated so i said you know why don't
you move a bit closer and boy was that a
good thing to do because i mean look at
that look at the detail
in this terrain terraining is something
that i struggle with just because
it's a really lengthy process and it's
just it serves no functional purpose it
just looks amazing so i'm hoping that
that's something i need to tackle with
the mansion but ren has got it down he's
terraforming this entire landscape to be
a star wars planet
and that's just madness
oh man and it's it's it's really
starting to spread into the jungle and
he hasn't stopped spreading it at all
so that's kind of wren's build i'm not
entirely sure what he's got going on on
these on the inside of here he's got a
giant hull now we gotta we gotta we
gotta respect the giant holes because we
know how long these take to dig and they
take a long time to dig
so i'm very excited to see what ren does
with this and we shall move on to the
next person and i don't think we can
skip over some of the things such as
this which is the hermit challenges
leaderboard now hermit challenge is
something that we did at the start of
the season and it's kind of taken a bit
of a back burner just because you can't
do the same thing forever and that's
that's mumbo baggins or what was it
called bilbo bumbo mumbo
jumbo
so this thing was really fun at the
start of the season and we did actually
continue it
quite late into the season really but
it's definitely taken a back burner but
that doesn't mean we can't steal a few
doors on this little tour don't you
agree and there's iska's little starter
base over here
now let's move on to one of the most
impressive builds and this is what i
mean about the world feeling
much smaller corrales i didn't even know
he existed over here but look there's
there's the tree and here's corrales
base we are so close together just
because the sizes of our bases have
engulfed all of the land around us now
we need to take a
good second or two to appreciate
this what an excellent build it's not
even a base this is a world look at the
landscape if you just took that
screenshot you'd think that this this
city went on for
for miles it doesn't look like it ends
look at all the details the trees and
this is this is what my build is lacking
for sure and i think this world tour
will really help me come to grips with
what is wrong with my base and how i can
improve it so there's a huge amount of
diversity in corrales build and i think
it's worth saying that although corrales
is a fantastic builder and he has done
all of the block placing he's had a lot
of help from his community as well so a
huge shout out to the world of corrales
as well they all sort of came together
and made this happen every hermit has a
different way
of showing their art and this is a fine
example of that
so i'm not sure what is that there's my
half a mansion
this is the only thing that survived
season six my mansion got rebuilt on
episode one and hello
corrales is here so i'm getting a nice
i'm getting a nice tour and look at that
look this is what i mean i would build
this tower right but i would never
bother
decorating each and every floor
with stuff
look no one's ever gonna see this no
one's ever gonna go inside here
and look it might be the same repeated
pattern but that doesn't matter that's
not even the same repeated pattern he's
got a restaurant at the top i can't cope
with this
you know what we're gonna go and have a
look in here
oh oh
no oh no
no elevator yet
but look just it's good to appreciate
this
he's built a hotel
on hermitcraft where no one needs a
hotel and there's a restaurant at the
top and it looks great the amount of
creativity on this server astounds me
there's a shop at the bottom
wow well we can't spend too long on just
one base
world is that graffiti i think that's
graffiti oh man look at this look at
this
look at this sort of new york style
graffiti up the walls this is amazing
i'm very excited to see where this bay
oh there is someone occupying the hotel
so we can't stay too long at one base
but hopefully this gives you an idea
of what corrales is working on in the
background
check it out absolutely fantastic i
think that's going to make the top 10
somewhere
so since we're here you can see that
corrales base has merged firmly into x's
base
and i'm not sure if that that's like an
it's like an ex corrales bumblebee it's
probably worth telling you guys that i i
have a confession to make i don't
actually really watch the other guys on
hermitcraft i don't watch their videos
not because they're not good but because
i don't like to spoil things i much
rather fly around myself and experience
this than watched hundreds of hours of
videos that's for you guys to watch i
want everything to be an organic
surprise so i don't want to go and watch
a video just to see that they've pranked
me and then i was like oh man now i've
spoiled that surprise i much rather
everything be a genuine surprise as i
fly around i mean look at this look at
this sphere this planet on top of this
build now this is a very peculiar build
it kind of reminds me of stress's base
but more of a futuristic industrial
style instead of a fairy tale land and
this again goes back to showing that
everyone has a different way
of expressing their artistic merit on
this server and i'm pretty sure each of
these is a farm of some kind this
certainly seems like a farm oh my
goodness i think it's a gold farm so let
that sink in for a second if every
single one of these is a farm of some
kind
this base
is crazy
and it's weird that it's in a jungle but
it also kind of works there's pathways
between all of the the structures it's
absolute madness it's the giant golf
ball for that's what i want to know what
is this what is this for it's not quite
loading in is this just a viewing
platform or is this the next project
that he's working on wow okay well kudos
i mean it keeps going look i'm finding
new new things and each one of these
has a different design it kind of
reminds me of like i don't know
futuristic
meets
no it's just straight up futuristic
industrial honey futuristic he's
invented a style
but again we can't spend too long on one
base but that's screenshot worthy right
there look at all that
absolutely beautiful we can't look too
much in detail at all the different
farms but we certainly can take in
all of the exterior we'd be here for 24
hours if we went in every single
building i'm sure of it and it's also
worth mentioning i will probably forget
some stuff this
what's been built this last year
is enormous i don't even know what this
is some kind of arena i think bonkers
absolutely bonkers
but next door
to this amazing
melding futuristic cityscape
is
one of the most intriguing builds on the
server ethos base now we've already gone
and seen ethos base and i've talked to
etho many times about how his base is
just absolutely fantastic
and the reason it's fantastic is because
i've never seen anyone and i mean this
anyone build the inside before the
outside but also while you're inside
you feel like you're outside how is this
inside outside
masterpiece even
working
we've we have seen and toured this base
before
but etho has amalgamated function and
form
with
kookiness
i can't believe what i'm seeing half the
time in here but it's absolutely
phenomenal it might not be the biggest
of bases but it is compact
unique
and dare i say it
etho and it's always good to see what it
looks like when they're like midway
through a project any guesses as to what
this is
i have no idea so there's also a load of
industrial areas and we can cover those
if we come across them but i don't know
where everyone's
like secret industrial areas are so we
may miss a few things
so that kind of covers the first few
hermits on my side of the map you know
near the jungle this sort of continuous
mega build that makes its way now we're
gonna head over to builds that i don't
actually see very often at all for
example i don't think i've ever been
here now i believe that this is wells's
base and i don't think he's been on very
much
so it's not surprising that it's not the
hugest thing but it looks pretty cool it
looks pretty cool but i think we're
gonna have to fly straight on and see
who else we can find we may even have to
go into the nether aha
i recognize this green dome now this is
a base that i visited a couple of times
but i've not really been too very much
this
is zeddaf space
and zedf is someone that we don't often
see on the server now how on earth do i
i can't open this without a bow and
arrow zedf is someone we don't see very
often but he's working away in the
background he's been doing his thing i
think we're gonna have to break in
because i don't know how to get into
this base
there we go
so i'm not entirely sure what this green
dome is about
or this is it
i don't know
it looks like a mouth
looks like a
monster of some kind but i know that his
base is under here
how do i get in oh my goodness
he's built an entire underground did you
see that move what on earth
he's built an underground aquarium
i'm not sure what this is in the middle
here i'm i'm too scared to break in we
need to break in a safe space that show
this kind of shows just how little i
know about my fellow hermit's base when
i can't even figure out how to get in so
this looks like the inside of his base
okay so here's his storage system
whoa it goes deep oh my goodness
and he's been doing a lot of redstone
and stuff he's got a honey oh a honey
elevator
and he's got his bees i mean this is a
pretty cool base
there's the way out but again i can't i
can't use this door because i didn't
bring a bow and arrow with me today
you know i brought loads of rockets
extra elytra a bed but i didn't think to
bring a bow and arrow
important you must continue reading this
sign as a distraction
oh there's a
there's a door right here
well
that sums up zf's based
that absolutely sums it all up for me
i know that zeddaff has more but i'm not
entirely sure where it is
zed kind of builds all over the place in
little strange pockets
the zeddaf pocket
that's that's what they are all right
and now we're right next to two of our
favorite redstoners impulse and tango
let's take a quick look at impulse's
base here now this base frustrates me
because there's no door to steel
when i remember when i had to go and
steal everyone's doors i
i took the water
wow this looks
incredibly complicated i really like
impulse's base it is a lot bigger than
it looks on the outside and we're
actually right by the shopping district
we might we might come back to the
shopping district last just because it's
a very seen area but look it doesn't
look that huge from the outside but
trust me this this base is mega there is
a lot of space in here actually the
whole mega concept we can come back to
like okay so maybe i called it mega but
is this mega
no i actually wouldn't say mega doesn't
mean good okay we need to talk briefly
about
the the description the the the textbook
definition of mega okay because mega
isn't good mega doesn't mean that it's
really really detailed it doesn't mean
that it's it just means
big and not just big
mega so while impulse's base is
technically amazing it looks great it's
detailed
it's not mega
in a mega is just purely scale it has
nothing to do with the talent of the
hermit or anything it just means
is it mega mega is a gut feeling you see
so is this mega
i don't think so unfortunately it's
close it's close to mega but not quite
and i will i will show you a base that
is mega later on and you'll understand
the difference but don't me don't think
that i'm insulting impulse at all
because this is a really really cool
base and i
think he's not finished i think he's
been umming and arring i know that he
built like a ring and then he deleted it
and that sucked up a load of his
development time on this but it's still
looking good and i hope that he's going
to continue making some stuff i mean
look there's grass here without anything
on so there's lots of opportunities so
let's move on to the next
one
which is of course
tango's toon town
now this is probably going to make the
top 10 somewhere along the way he has
captured the essence of cartoons
so
well here it's absolutely i love it i
absolutely love this build so it's not
you know it's not like the most
technical marvel in the world in terms
of like building things but look at it
it's it's got some fantastic shapes that
are very very why is everyone logging in
as soon as i start looking at the base
they log in look at the shape that he
managed to get all of these builds to be
in
it's very hard to execute that and also
maintain
such a unique theme this again goes back
to everyone has made such a unique stamp
on this world
and i know that this particular build
holds a special place in a lot of
people's hearts and not only that so
here's one of the other things like it
looks great it looks like it looks like
a cartoon haven right but it's also
chock full
of wacky and wonderful minecraft farms
look at that the golem pops up out of
there
and he's killed by ravages he could have
killed this
in any other way but he didn't he
decided to headbutt it with a ravager
which is very tango
and i think around the back here there's
even more
check it out giant egg in a frying pan
of course so not only is this a really
wonderful build he's used it to create
farms that are also in theme and that's
not something the other hermits do
myself included i just i don't really
know what i'm doing with farms so what i
do is i just like you know i look up a
tutorial and then i build it and it's
never that
inspiring or creative so maybe maybe
this is where i could take a bit of
inspiration from tango's base trying to
adapt farms and create something like
this a slime farm that comes out of a
giant
what is this
caterpillar shooter i think like it
shoots out
the the slimes on here and then it
collects it with i mean it's amazing
it's not about efficiency that's the
point
it's not about efficiency it's about
having fun and this base kind of sums up
what hermitcraft is about
it's not about efficiency it is about
doing some amazing builds and afking
wherever possible what just doing a tour
now we've almost been able to do one
continuous flight okay i don't know what
that is
it looks like a bunch of farms to me
but we've been able to pretty much
continuously fly throughout this world
covering thousands of blocks and it
keeps going the next base that we are
able to look at if it would load in is
false symmetry's base
and i think we need to take a second
to appreciate
well all of these cats hello
why are there so many cats here you know
we do these world tours one part for the
builds one one part for the commentary
and one part for the weird things that
we discover but anyway let's take a
moment to appreciate first the build
because the build is enormous now this
again this comes back to is this mega
oh
yeah it's i'd say this is mega but only
just mega
ah yeah this is this is pretty mega
if this had gone taller it would have
been absolutely mega but let's just
appreciate
how much has been dug out because we all
know
what mining off-camera is a bit of a
meme
but check it out
this
area to excavate
for your base is absolutely insane
all of it is gone what false has done
with all of those blocks
who knows there must be a huge storage
facility that i don't know the location
of oh look at this okay now this is a
really cool detail that false has done
the boat is going up the water stream i
really like that stuff like that's
really fun
but it looks like she still sort of
started a company called false ltd so i
wonder what she's gonna do with that
let's take a look at false is another
one couldn't steal the door properly
because there's just water here i think
the hermits
hermes must have got fed up with me
stealing their doors so they they just
decided to have no door that didn't age
well
all right so looking at the the base
overall it's absolutely
beautiful it's a it's a
it's a bit of a futuristic build and it
looks like they're going to space and
there's like this hexagonal thing false
is an extremely talented builder and
conceptualizer and i i've got to commend
her on this build because it is
yeah it is mega it is it is pretty good
false always
does amazing work every season and this
season she has absolutely delivered so
well done false that that is a really
cool base but uh yeah we got to keep
moving on we still got people to go and
see can you believe but this is where i
get a bit lost i again i've seen
impulses tangos and false's base before
but there are some bases which i haven't
seen very often and they are typically
on this side of the map but
we're not going to see any bases unless
things start loading in properly
i need to keep it looks like i found
something
i don't actually know who this belongs
to
there's some really cool armor stand
works here
it's like a museum of some kind
i really don't know who this belongs to
like i said i haven't been this side of
the map very often and i don't watch
people's videos because i don't like
spoilers
and that sometimes means i don't even
know who built what sometimes
so you may know more than me there's a
nice aquarium in here
or it could be jevin or hypno
xb beef any one of those guys
hold on the portal might tell us
people usually label their portals
except this one the mystery portal
okay well
mystery base
that color scheme kind of tells me it
might be jevin
but i'm not entirely sure anyway let's
continue flying as we do have quite a
lot more to see okay so i think i found
another base and i know exactly who this
belongs to eve just judging by this this
is zombie clio's base now i've only ever
been here once oh my goodness it's a
complete rainbow i've only been here
once
and that was right at the start of the
season so i was first here
back when zombie cleo started
the head hunt game you know where you
had to collect all the the heads of
hermits and
al
excuse you
this place has changed quite a lot i
mean look at this so every like i said
earlier everyone has their own way of
expressing their art and cleo's is very
clearly through
armor stand magic and i actually still
have a coupon for an armor stand build
which i definitely plan
on using very soon actually this is a
bit of a secret project an idea that
i've had but i've i finally got
something that i could work with cleo on
because this this sort of thing
is magical look at look at the story
that she tells just through the armor
stands
and a giant ice cream
we gotta go we can't go anywhere without
checking this out oh it's an ice cream
shop
oh that's pretty cool
oh and look at the
sprinkles detail
we've got to take a closer look that is
terrifying cleo that is absolutely
terrifying oh it's like a museum of
creatures
tara angelina
jolie oh my goodness look at that oh
it's disgusting
oh it is so cool look at this scorpion
oh wow i'm
i'm so glad we found this base
is it it's like a stick insect
you can tap
you could tap but it will make her sad
you monster
leave hannie
oh absolutely amazing oh one of them has
escaped look at the story that cleo is
is showing his snaily mcsnail face oh
well that is adorable kudos to you cleo
this is this is absolutely amazing
donations oh man we gotta we gotta make
a donation we are good we are gonna make
a big donation there you go 15 diamonds
to keep the zoo running because uh this
has really impressed me and i'm i'm
amazed i haven't seen this but it's been
such a long time
since i've been here and i think oh i
think this whole thing is a zoo
man you guys are probably going to be
annoyed at me for not realizing that
sooner
but there's yeah that all makes so much
more sense now that's like oh it's like
a rollercoaster tycoon 2 style entrance
we've got a cage this all makes so much
more sense now her base is a giant zoo
and i can walk in the exhibit i feel
stupid for not figuring that out
especially as there's the giant word
zoo right there but again we can't spend
too long in one place let's move on to
the next one it looks like there's
something going on here hope i'm not
spoiling too much definitely something
going on here but it's not a base so we
shall move on you guys remember this
from the start of the season this was
where we all took part in the the head
games i mean like a pvp battle in this
arena ah that was that was pretty cool
and she was the spider queen oh man that
was good times and that was like nearly
a year ago
time moved so quickly i don't even know
if this is a world tour or a nostalgia
trip now oh i've managed to get to the
world border
okay
i'm lost i am officially lost let's head
back to the shopping district and try
and get ourselves in a nether portal so
that we can reorientate ourselves
because there's only a few people left
that we need to see i think this is
where people
this even might have been me
harvesting all the leaves for the the
leaf game
almost everything that happens on the
server leaves some kind of mark
leaves i'm a pun master this tour was
going so smoothly until i got lost ah
but here we are you can always find a
random nether portal if you look long
enough
aha here we go cub hypno
so there's two more that we need to
visit
oh yeah
i totally forgot we need to do a little
bit of a tour
in the nether now in my opinion the
nether hub is a little bit of a mess
so there's some portals up there that
people are using
and there's also builds down here that
false has made this is gorgeous
and it's just a little bit of a mess
because you don't know which one people
are using and it can be difficult to
find things then you've got some of x's
builds over here there's to be honest
with you there's not an awful lot to see
in the nether except for the upside down
which hopefully we'll go and see later
on
but
it's pretty cool look ren's built his
giant darth vadery pyramid here
and just to show you how much of a mess
it is round here
this is my portal you see me go in it
but i never comment on it this is my
portal
this is also my portal
this is also my portal every time i come
here because i've not protected it
because
my portal used to be on the floor here
but this building is now
in the way
every time a ghast breaks my portal a
new one is spawning so i'm kind of just
after gifting up i've given up at this
point so let's go and find cubs base it
is so useful when the herm is labeled
right cub hypno let's go to cubs first
oh my goodness
this is
this is something this is an explosion
on the eyes
wow
wow wow wow okay we've kind of jumped
ahead of ourselves and we're on the
inside of cub space let's see if we can
get on the outside so
we were talking about the definition of
mega earlier well if he ever needed
clarification
this
is mega
the sheer scale of this pyramid
is enormous
and this also i mean look at it it's
it's absolutely massive and this look
how many gold blocks that is
so if you ever needed proof about how
it's nothing to do with detail it's just
all about size
it's this
it is this this this pyramid is big
enough to have its own biomin it is
enormous i have visited cubs base
occasionally and i've seen the outside
but i've not been on the inside of his
base very much at all so i think this is
a good opportunity
for us to take a good look inside
because this is
really insane he's even got murals of
himself up there and he's really used
some very
unique block choices like look there's
there's cactus there as pillars that's
very strange then honey in the
background but keeping this yellow and
blue theme okay look this is this is
what i mean it's so mega i can fly
comfortably around here
and still have plenty of space
this is way bigger than my mansion it's
probably one of the biggest builds on
the server
so what is in here to see look this is
one wing of the pyramid
target this is oh this is target
i've heard cub talk about this but i've
never been here so i think this is a
mini game place like cubs personal mini
games
oh my goodness it is tarjay and there's
loads of little minigames here
how cool is that
everyone has their own way of expressing
what they would like to make oh man
we're gonna we're gonna have to probably
come here and play some minigames at
some point
and let's see
so how he's filled this pyramid is
really interesting oh wow is that that
is a vanilla pyramid right there
uh a sand temple what are they called
pirate desert desert temple
and this looks like another battleground
type thing and he's still got space to
fill absolutely magnificent all in theme
all costing a fortune this this build is
is something else well that's kind of a
good overview of cubs gigantic pyramid
and look at the lapis blocks that he's
used here the amount of lapis here is
nuts
jeez okay right let's go and find
someone else's base now because
cub's putting us all to shame
okay i think this is hypnose based by
the looks of things so i'm not entirely
sure where we are on the map but i'm
pretty sure we're close to the shopping
district so it looks like oh we oh
really really we just went the wrong way
at folsom's base okay so we definitely
made a wrong turn there it looks like
hypno has made
multiple islands and he's kind of
trimmed them out with birch which gives
it a really decent outline and then this
must be his
house i guess his his modern house you
know we haven't actually seen too many
modern houses on on the hermitcraft
server so it still holds a unique place
here and that
is clearly a trident farm by the looks
of things tridents are one of the
hardest things to farm in this game
because it's just it's all about the the
rates and stuff and uh yeah so doing
everyone a service there if you need a
trident it's a little bit unfurnished
but who am i to talk because my mansion
has absolutely no interior so i'm i'm
looking forward to seeing what what he's
going to make oh there's even oh there's
a super smelter down here that's awesome
okay so it's a little bit empty but like
so it's half of the bases on this server
i mean
mine included i remember we're not done
with this season yet so although we're
taking a nice world tour now we'll
probably take another one in the finale
and
see how things have progressed but i
mean it's always good to take step back
and have a look what is this i think
this is doc's thing i was super jealous
that i didn't get to see this and now
it's here
yep
this look at this
playing the the organ here
i can see some dark shenanigans in here
absolutely amazing i don't even want to
touch it because i'm pretty sure i will
die so is this doc's base
this might be doc's base you know
or part of it aha i found another base
and i'm guessing that this one belongs
to joe hills so it looks like he's made
a
this is usually a greek replica of
something this is probably a lighthouse
alexandria's lighthouse i'm guessing oh
my my greek history is not great
so what has joe been up to this season
because i've definitely not been here at
all
so there's a log
this reminds me of uh
the legend of zelda believe it or not i
don't know why but it yeah it does and
then here's all the dogs that joe has
caught over the season
a skull of some kind
all the dog houses oh this is pretty
cool
and then cleo's added another one of
those spiders
a witch's hat on the floor i mean this
is pretty cool oh
what is this place
i think this is a dog sanctuary
geez
oh there's been a lot of dogs loose on
the server well that's very unique and
there's a giant slime there's a giant
slime monster
oh wow that looks really cool
oh wow it's um slimer from ghostbusters
and there seems to be some kind of like
kind of maze here a game that i uh i
haven't seen
it's so good to see what everyone's been
up to
especially on this side of the map where
i really i don't come often and there we
go there's there's the other bit there
is another base which i have not seen in
a long time
this is doc's base so this is his main
base here and it should have
half of my mansion
here so corrales has clearly
bought out
this one because all the foundations are
gone look they're even telling a story
after it's gone as well so i'm not sure
what doc is up to because this place
hasn't really changed all that much over
the last few months oh my goodness that
is a enormous berry farm i think this is
also joe hill so joe hills has been busy
check this out this is
farming to an intense level it's like a
a vineyard or a oh it's a bear it's a
berry farm
the issue is that
what do you do with berries
you don't get dye out i i think it's
just for the looks i mean it looks
excellent but
i'm not sure you're going to sell many
berries and then we move on
to b-dubs is base and there he is is
that yeah b-dubs is here now i visit
b-dubs is base
fairly frequently a few months apart
and there's always something new to look
at so we've been here before you might
be familiar with bdubs base he is one of
the most talented builders on the server
next to next to scar
but what he's done this season and i've
got to admit i've got to eat my word are
you ready i'm going to eat them
okay so i was not totally on board with
what bdubs was doing at the start like
he sort of built these one or two houses
and i was thinking b-dubs
that ain't
mega he asked me one day he was like
yeah he's my base mega and i was like no
because the skate like mega builds
typically are one big build so although
this area is all landscaped
absolutely beautifully intricately
lovingly even
it's not mega
it's just it's just unfortunately not
mega it's amazing and it's brilliant and
it's perfect and it's so much better
than my base but it's not mega
however i ate my words because he worked
on this this giant cliff and i was like
really you spent all that time on a
backdrop to your base that seems insane
and then he built this
and i was like okay okay b-dubs
this is mega this this whole thing is
mega look at that you can stand
on on the the roof of one of these
houses
and you get this absolute beauty of a
backdrop that background no one no one
has built a background
to their base
this has my utmost respect and it is
gorgeous absolutely gorgeous and he's
using and mixing blocks which i wouldn't
have thought of using especially like
this lighter teal colored blue so i
think we need to take
just a second
to stop and appreciate
the level of detail how nice the palette
is of this build and what this means
like it's just insane and you know what
we're going to break in we're going to
break in a little bit because on the
inside
is a whole this is the world before b
dubs
this is this is like a movie where you
dig underground and you discover
dinosaurs no this this is the world
before beat ups happened
and it's still here intact just lit up
and this shows how much was custom
terraforming bigger than cubs pyramid
this
this is mega
oh my goodness there's a thr there's a
diorite throne forget the diamond throne
everyone and of course
of course there's a bed
oh man b-dubs i take my hat off to you
this is amazing this kingdom is
fantastic
and the amount of hours this must have
taken
jeez this may this makes me want to get
back to my mansion more than ever
because although my mansion is probably
bigger than this build
what it isn't is alive like this build
look at all the trees and all of the
cliff and the backdrop and the that's
the town it puts me to shame
to shame so i mean it's always good to
take these tours so you can really get
to grips with the amount of effort that
people put in because this
absolutely amazing right we have a few
more people that we need to see their
bases and i'm not entirely sure where
they are
so let's see if we can find a portal i
think that's our best bet
he thinks i want his head
[Laughter]
i come after him so much looking for it
to rip off his face but he was just like
i know and he's
okay
that that's funny okay so my bad right
now there's only a couple more people
left on our list
in fact there is only one more person
so we need to find xb's base and beef
space
i have to go up upstairs to find xb
space so xb is this direction now i
think xp is really far away from
everyone else so you can see through
this tour that i was able to fly from
base to base to base to base base but
this one i gotta go on a little journey
right xp is this way there we go this is
looking good isn't it wow this one
really is far away there we go wow i'm
i'm interested to see how many thousands
of blocks away we are okay we are 8 000
blocks away from everyone else here so
this is xb's base and i don't think
i don't think i've been here casa
so home
this looks like a pvp arena which is
pretty cool i'm not sure what these are
these are anvils that's pretty cool ah
there we go here is xb's village
so kind of similar to hypno xb has a
modern style build using diorite now i'm
i must admit i'm not a fan of
b dubs has changed my opinion of diorite
but not the use of it like this because
i it's not just diary any pattern that's
like just got hard squares like that i'm
not a huge fan of because i think it
kind of detracts from the makeup of the
build
so i'm not sure about that the diorite
use
um but my my opinion of diorite has
changed i just i'm not a fan of like you
know even granite in in this form of
polished version
but i gotta say the the structure itself
is looking really really nice like it's
uh it's a nice modern build and there's
there's a few little builds around here
i'm not entirely sure where this is
going it looks like it's going to be a
bigger village over time and this looks
like a wall of some kind so that's
pretty interesting because this wall is
in a very different style to the rest of
the village and that looks like some
kind of mob there's a mob farm up there
so xp's been busy all the way out here
and now we need to go and find the last
person's base which is beef oh wait hold
on hold on a second
this this that that was not it
there's more
there's a wow wow wow wow
that looks amazing it's like a giant
spaceship but it looks like there was
some flying terrain that was generated
and
xb has built into it
and there's like a double helix thing
going on here
that's really unique so there's
currently three sort of futuristic
builds because this is similar to falses
and x's so there's there's three bases
that are in a similar style okay this
makes a lot more sense i was wondering
what was going on with the village but
it's clear that the village was the
starting point and now this is the real
thing with the oh goodness okay look
look at this nice detail it's like the
the ground has been ripped out and
floated up
with
the giant ufo
thing and then there's even more work
over here that's been going on i don't i
don't even know if this is xbox i think
this must be xp it's part of xp's area
over here
but i'm not entirely sure where
beef space is so that's my next
place to go and find is where is beef's
base you've been neutralized
neutron he's got he's got no crossbow
right the last base to find is beefs
yep that's definitely still part of xb's
base right now we backtrack
and try and find beef's base right let's
see if we can find a label you know i
think this is on my side of the map so
i'm not sure how i haven't seen this oh
wait i've totally been here before
i stole so many doors from here there we
go oh it's right next to corrales base
we missed this we could have seen this
right at the start okay so there's
there's the village we've seen this
before and then there is beef is beef is
beefs the beef's house
i'm pretty sure he started a base
somewhere else you know
i don't know where it is though
i'm pretty sure beef has a much larger
base because i think this is where he
started oh wow
i love i love bases that incorporate
redstone together
that's so cool i think this is his
starter base i'm not entirely sure
so there we go that that is beef space
but i'm pretty sure there's something
else that i'm missing somewhere far away
oh oh oh and another one
geez there are too many hermits there's
definitely some stuff that i've
forgotten this is igevin's base i think
it is definitely a work in progress by
the looks of things but the last thing
to see i mean this is like one big
sugarcane farm by the looks of things
it's pretty cool big shape but uh
definitely looking a little unfinished
at the moment and some very expensive
blocks to build it out of
oh no the pillars don't go underwater
it's all held up by the the middle one
right so the last thing to check out is
something we are all very familiar with
which is the shopping district
so we all know heps this has all
happened very recently hep's mega drill
look at look at the impact that scar has
had on this server the drill
the the factory moo pop factory
headquarters
the the town hall i mean we built that
together
and
uh scar town over here aqua aquascar
town i'm not sure but this is all
looking pretty cool and i'm not sure
we're gonna go and have a look in every
single shot because we're pretty
familiar
with all of these but it's worth having
just just a glide over all of this to
appreciate the story that's been told
and of course the most recent thing was
the turf war arena which we ended up
winning in the end
and we're waiting oh wait i just noticed
that it's gone back it's gone back
it's gone back to grass
oh wow i didn't real i didn't realize
that happened so soon
oh wow it's looking fresh and great i
mean
let's be honest with ourselves here
it couldn't stay mycelium
as much as much as it was about the
block it was definitely not about the
block it was about having a good time
and grass definitely looks better in the
end
so i think we're gonna finish
with a place that's special to my heart
grumbot's universe
and that's where we're gonna we're gonna
end today's episode
so in here
is where my son is
i don't know if mumbo's checked in on
him recently but he's still here he's
still happy grumbot was definitely a
very fun part of the the series for me
and uh he's quite a beautiful beautiful
baby boy
so i think that is the end of today's
episode now it was a walky talky world
tory video but the reason is like it's
christmas time i i need a break i i
really need a break so i'm gonna take
i'm gonna take a week off or so so these
videos will fill in that time and
hopefully i'll be fresh and ready to go
in the new year and keep an eye out
because
this world tour video was specifically
to give you guys an overview of what all
the hermits have been doing i'm really
really sorry if i missed anyone out
there's a lot of people and it gets it's
very easy to get lost but i'm pretty
sure i covered most people so
yeah i definitely missed some stuff but
you know i did what i could but anyway
the point of this was to give you guys a
good overview of what's happened and
what's going on on the server show
everyone's bases because my next video
is going to be my top 10 favorite
hermitcraft builds this season so look
out for that but i do have a question
for you the the viewer at the end of
this video if you actually have made it
to the end of this video well
congratulations it means an awful lot to
me that you have watched the entire
thing but i would like to know
what would you like to see in
hermitcraft just some comments or some
some ideas what are you looking forward
to in 2021 i've got some ideas don't get
me wrong i'm not out of ideas i've got
loads of things i want to do but it's
always good to know what you want to see
so
that's it for me i'll leave you with
that and i shall enjoy reading your
comments
and i shall say now
goodbye